Guide to the Miscellaneous Manuscripts Collection
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- T, Series X
  - Tyrrell, Walcott, 1835 (Box 57, Folder 1300)
- U - V, Series XI
  - Ullman, Isaac Morris, 1910-1930 (Box 58, Folder 1301)
  - Union des Israélites Indigènes de Roumanie, 1916-1918 (Box 58, Folder 1302)
  - Union Iron Works, Selma, Alabama, 1885-1888 (Box 58, Folder 1303)
  - Union Theological Seminary, Class of 1857, 1902-1907 (Box 58, Folder 1304)
  - United Nations: Republic of Haiti, 1945 (Box 58, Folder 1305)
  - U. S. Army, 1812-1865 (Box 58, Folder 1306)
  - U. S. Attorney General, 1788 (Box 58, Folder 1307)
  - U. S. Constitution, 1953 (Box 58, Folder 1308)
  - U. S. Consulate, Malaga, Spain, 1827 (Box 58, Folder 1309)
  - U. S. Continental Congress, 1775 (Box 58, Folder 1310)
  - U. S. Department of Internal Revenue, 1801, 1868 (Box 58, Folder 1311)
  - U. S. Department of State, 1812-1830, 1895 (Box 58, Folder 1312)
  - U. S. Loan Office, Philadelphia, 1861 (Box 58, Folder 1313)
  - U. S. Naval Academy, Annapolis, 1894-1898 (Box 58, Folder 1314)
  - U. S. Navy, 1840-1846 (Box 58, Folder 1315)
  - U. S. Patent Office, 1895 (Box 58, Folder 1316)
  - U. S. Pension Bureau, 1848 (Box 58, Folder 1317)
  - U. S. Quartermaster's Department, 1783 (Box 58, Folder 1318)
  - U. S. Treasury Department, 1790-1942 (Box 58, Folder 1319)
  - U. S.-History-War of 1812, 1814-1815 (Box 58, Folder 1320-1321)
  - United World Federalists, Newtown, Conn., 1948 (Box 58, Folder 1322)
  - Uppermill, England, preaching compact, 1821 (Box 58, Folder 1323)
  - Upton, Winslow, 1880-1909, undated (Box 58, Folder 1324)
  - Ureña, Max Henriquez, 1947 (Box 58, Folder 1325)
  - Urquhart, Frank John, 1916 (Box 58, Folder 1326)
  - Van Buren, Martin, 1830-1831 (Box 59, Folder 1327)
  - Van Name, Addison, 1859-1860 (Box 59, Folder 1328)
  - Van Santvoord, Cornelius, 1833 (Box 59, Folder 1329)
  - Vane, Sir Henry, 1645 (Box 59, Folder 1330)
  - Vaughan, Bernard, 1906 (Box 59, Folder 1331)
  - Vedder, Elihu, 1900 (Box 59, Folder 1332)
  - Vermont, 1835-1869 (Box 59, Folder 1333)
  - Victor, Bishop of Peking, 1938 (Box 59, Folder 1334)
  - Victoria, Queen of Great Britain, 1839, 1843 (Box 59, Folder 1335)
  - Viénot, John Collection, 1767, 1926-1927 (Box 59, Folder 1336-1338)
  - Villegas, Jaime Angel, 1948 (Box 60, Folder 1339)
  - Villiers, Frederic, 1892 (Box 60, Folder 1340)
  - Vinaver, Rosa, 1944 (Box 60, Folder 1341)
  - Vinton, Lucretia D., 1835 (Box 60, Folder 1342)
  - Virginia Colony County Court, 1851-1852 (Box 60, Folder 1343)
  - Viginia. House of Delegates, 1783 (Box 60, Folder 1344)
  - Vorys, John Martin, 1941 (Box 60, Folder 1345)
- W, Series XII
  - Wadsworth, Peleg, 1806 (Box 61, Folder 1346)
  - Wagner, Napoleon, 1914 (Box 61, Folder 1347)
  - Waine, William, 1752, 1759 (Box 61, Folder 1348)
  - Wait, John Turner, 1876 (Box 61, Folder 1349)
  - Waite, George C. and Douglass, 1842-1861 (Box 61, Folder 1350)
  - Waite, Morrison Remick, 1882 (Box 61, Folder 1351)
  - Waldo, C. B., undated (Box 61, Folder 1352)
  - Walker, Francis Amasa, 1880, 1896 (Box 61, Folder 1353)
  - Walker, H. F., 1891 (Box 61, Folder 1354)
  - Walker, Wilfred, 1875 (Box 61, Folder 1355)
  - Wallace, Henry Agard, 1959-1960 (Box 61, Folder 1356)
  - Wallace, Henry Cantwell, 1917 (Box 61, Folder 1357)
  - Wallace, J. K., 1855 (Box 61, Folder 1358)
  - Wanton, Philip, 1851 (Box 61, Folder 1359)
  - Ward, Elizabeth Stuart (Phelps), undated (Box 61, Folder 1360)
  - Ward, Julius Hammond, 1863-1876 (Box 61, Folder 1361)
  - Washington, George, 1751-1790 (Box 61, Folder 1362)
  - Washington and his cabinet, 1777-1814 (Box 61, Folder 1363)
  - Washington and his cabinet, 1777-1814 (Box 61a)
  - Watts, John, 1736-1738 (Box 61, Folder 1364)
  - Wayne, Anthony, 1792 (Box 62, Folder 1365)
  - Webb, Benjamin, 1870 (Box 62, Folder 1366)
  - Webster, Daniel, 1837-1851 (Box 62, Folder 1367)
  - Webster, John Howard, 1925 (Box 62, Folder 1368)
  - Webster, Rose Glem, 1897-1905 (Box 62, Folder 1369)
  - Weeks, James H., Jr., 1897-1901 (Box 62, Folder 1370)
  - Welles, Gideon, undated (Box 62, Folder 1371)
  - Wellesley College, Wellesley, Mass., 1924 (Box 62, Folder 1372)
  - Wellman, Joshua Wyman, 1887 (Box 62, Folder 1373)
  - Wells, Albert Sessions, 1924 (Box 62, Folder 1374)
  - Wells, Gabriel, 1936 (Box 62, Folder 1375)
  - Wells, William S., 1869-1910, undated (Box 62, Folder 1376)
  - Wesleyan University, Middletown, Conn., 1831 (Box 62, Folder 1377)
  - Westcott, John, 1869 (Box 62, Folder 1378)
  - Whedon, Susan H., 1909, 1930 (Box 62, Folder 1379)
  - Wheller, William, 1853-1857 (Box 62, Folder 1380)
  - Whig Party, Conn., 1840, 1850 (Box 62, Folder 1381)
  - White, John Barber, 1911 (Box 62, Folder 1382)
  - White, Nicholas, 1700 (Box 62, Folder 1383)
  - White, Robert J., 1932-1933 (Box 62, Folder 1384)
  - White, Simeon, 1839-1841 (Box 62, Folder 1385)
  - White, Wilbur McKee, undated (Box 62, Folder 1386)
  - White, William Allen, 1922 (Box 62, Folder 1387)
  - White, William Q., 1868 (Box 62, Folder 1388)
  - Whiting, William, 1703 (Box 62, Folder 1389)
  - Whitlock, Lewis, 1845 (Box 62, Folder 1390)
  - Whitmore and Buckingham, 1835 (Box 62, Folder 1391)
  - Whitney, Asa, 1852 (Box 62, Folder 1392)
  - Whitney, Charles W., 1912-1925 (Box 62, Folder 1393)
  - Whittelsey, Chauncey, 1786 (Box 62, Folder 1394)
  - Whittlesey, Elisha, 1826-1862 (Box 62, Folder 1395)
  - Wickham, Joseph Dresser, 1887, 1889 (Box 62, Folder 1396)
  - Wieser, Franz, Ritter von, 1890-1904 (Box 62, Folder 1397)
  - Wiggin, Frederick Holme, 1950 (Box 62, Folder 1398)
  - Wilkinson, Alexander K., 1857-1892 (Box 62, Folder 1399)
  - Wilkinson, James, 1817 (Box 63, Folder 1400)
  - Willard, Samuel George, 1845 (Box 63, Folder 1401)
  - Williams, Elisha, 1750 (Box 63, Folder 1402)
  - Williams, Jared Warner, 1826 (Box 63, Folder 1403)
  - Williams, John (1664-1729), 1716/7 (Box 63, Folder 1404)
  - Williams, John (1751-1816), 1809 (Box 63, Folder 1405)
  - Williams, John (1817-1899), 1844-1895 (Box 63, Folder 1406)
  - Williams, Samuel, 1807-1810 (Box 63, Folder 1407)
  - Williams, Seth, 1929-1938 (Box 63, Folder 1408)
  - Williams, Solomon, 1770 (Box 63, Folder 1409)
  - Williams, William (1734-1808), 1807 (Box 63, Folder 1410)
  - Williams, William (1803-1888), 1887 (Box 63, Folder 1411)
  - Williams, William Minor, 1844 (Box 63, Folder 1412)
  - Willis, Nathaniel Parker, 1861 (Box 63, Folder 1413)
  - Wilson, Augusta Jane (Evans), undated (Box 63, Folder 1414)
  - Wilson, Sarah, 1863 (Box 63, Folder 1415)
  - Winchester, Jacob Bancroft, 1833 (Box 63, Folder 1416)
  - Winship, George Parker, 1919 (Box 63, Folder 1417)
  - Winthrop, John, undated (Box 63, Folder 1418)
  - Winthrop, Robert Charles, 1876 (Box 63, Folder 1419)
  - Wirt, William, 1830-1832, undated (Box 63, Folder 1520)
  - Wolcott, Oliver, 1785, 1796 (Box 63, Folder 1421)
  - Wolfe, James, 1749-1759 (Box 63, Folder 1422-1423)
  - Woman's Universal Alliance, undated (Box 63, Folder 1424)
  - Wood, Leonard, 1916 (Box 63, Folder 1425)
  - Woodbridge, John, 1847 (Box 63, Folder 1426)
  - Woodruff, Eleazer, 1776 (Box 63, Folder 1427)
  - Wool, John Ellis, 1862 (Box 63, Folder 1428)
  - Wooster Family, 1728-1782 (Box 63, Folder 1429)
  - Worcester, Joseph Emerson, 1829-1847 (Box 63, Folder 1430)
  - Wright, Arthur Williams, 1870-1874 (Box 63, Folder 1431)
  - Wyckoff, Theodore, 1960 (Box 64, Folder 1432-1435)
  - Wyman, Daniel, 1836 (Box 64, Folder 1436)
- X - Z, Series XIII
  - Ximénez, Ramón, 1748 (Box 65, Folder 1437)
  - Yale, Hannah, 1788 (Box 65, Folder 1438)
  - Yale, James Corbet, 1891, 1900 (Box 65, Folder 1439)
  - Yale National Bank, 1876 (Box 65, Folder 1440)
  - Yale University. Class of 1785, 1784-1786 (Box 65, Folder 1441)
  - Yale University. Class of 1859, undated (Box 65, Folder 1442)
  - Yates, Peter Waldron, 1804 (Box 65, Folder 1443)
  - York, Alvin Cullum, 1928 (Box 65, Folder 1444)
  - Youle, George, 1812 (Box 65, Folder 1445)
  - Young, Benham Daniel, 1877, 1888 (Box 65, Folder 1446)
  - Young, Innis, 1958 (Box 65, Folder 1447)
  - Youngs, James, 1815 (Box 65, Folder 1448)
  - Zazzera, Francisco, 1616-1623 (Box 65, Folder 1449)
- Numerical, 1-100, Series XIV
  - No. 1: Knox, Henry, 1789-1794 (Box 66, Folder 1450)
  - No. 2: Brogan, Denis, 1966 (Box 66, Folder 1451)
  - No. 3: Allis, Elisha, and Sarah Cutler, 1765 (Box 66, Folder 1452)
  - No. 4: Bulford, Martha, 1827-1828, undated (Box 66, Folder 1453)
  - No. 5: Congregational Churches in Massachusetts, 1557-1808, undated (Box 66, Folder 1454)
  - NO. 6: Cronholm, Neander Nicholas, 1907 (Box 66, Folder 1455-1457)
  - No. 7: Daggett, William Gibbons, 1879 (Box 66, Folder 1458)
  - No. 8: Mississippi Company, 1768 (Box 66, Folder 1459)
  - No. 9: Virginia (Colony) General Assembly. House of Burgesses, 1766-1767 (Box 66, Folder 1460)
  - No. 10: Deane, Silas
    See: Box 100
  - No. 11: Viener, John David, 1961 (Box 66, Folder 1462)
  - No. 12: Bailey, W. H., 1867 (Box 66, Folder 1463)
  - No. 13: Dickinson, William R., 1802 (Box 66, Folder 1464)
  - No. 14: Dino, Charles Maurice Camille de Talleyrand-Périgord, due de, 1876-1880 (Box 66, Folder 1465)
  - No. 15: Windsor, Edward, Duke of, 1943 (Box 66, Folder 1466)
  - No. 16: Ferdinand, Duke of Brunswick-Luneberg
    See: English Misc. MSS Collection, Mss. Gr. No. 753
  - No. 17: Folsom, David, 1823 (Box 67, Folder 1467)
  - No. 18: [Anonymous], The Hague Conference, undated (Box 67, Folder 1468)
  - No. 19: Gallup, Isaac, 1776 (Box 67, Folder 1469)
  - No. 20: Edouart, Augustin Amant Constance Fidèle, 1841 (Box 67, Folder 1470)
  - No. 21: Gibbs, Abraham
  - No. 22: Greene, Nathaniel
    See: Nathaniel Greene Papers, Ms. Gr. No. 616
  - No. 23: Gowing, Peter Gordon, 1960 (Box 67, Folder 1472)
  - No. 24: Griswold, Roger
    See: Roger Griswold Papers, Ms. Gr. No. 256
  - No. 25: Baruch, Bernard Mannes, 1918, undated (Box 67, Folder 1473)
  - No. 26: Hale, Edward Everett, 1847, undated (Box 67, Folder 1474)
  - No. 27: Hopkinson, Francis, 1781 (Box 67, Folder 1475)
  - No. 28: Hunt, James Bennett, 1844 (Box 67, Folder 1476)
  - No. 29: McKenney, Thomas Loraine, 1824-1830 (Box 67, Folder 1477)
  - No. 30: Martin, Luther, 1803 (Box 67, Folder 1478)
  - No. 31: Mann, Horace, 1836-1858, 1896, undated (Box 67, Folder 1479-1480)
  - No. 32: Onis, Luis de, 1816 (Box 68, Folder 1481)
  - No. 33: Richard, Pierre, 1815 (Box 68, Folder 1482)
  - No. 34: Ridpath, John Clark, 1881 (Box 68, Folder 1483)
  - No. 35: Rigail, L. A.
  - No. 36: Summerfield, John, 1824 (Box 68, Folder 1485)
  - No. 37: Sumner, William Graham
    See: William Graham Sumner Papers, Ms. Gr. No. 291
  - No. 38: Truchard du Molin, Romain, 1858-1877 (Box 68, Folder 1486)
  - No. 39: Trumbull, John, 1784 (Box 68, Folder 1487)
  - No. 40: U.S. Army. Continental Army, 1763-1781 (Box 68, Folder 1488-1489)
  - No. 41: Weiner, Robert S., 1968 (Box 68, Folder 1490)
  - No. 42: Wyllys Family, 1590-1792, undated (Box 68, Folder 1491)
  - No. 43: Teas, Thomas, 1821 (Box 68, Folder 1492)
  - No. 44: [Anonymous]: New Haven lawyer, 1836-1879 (Box 69, Folder 1493)
  - No. 45: Ward, William Hayes, 1906 (Box 69, Folder 1494)
  - No. 46: [Discarded, 1983] (Box 69, Folder 1494)
  - No. 47: Ford, Paul Leicester, 1759-1808, undated (Box 69, Folder 1495)
  - No. 48: Arnold, Samuel James, 1827 (Box 69, Folder 1496)
  - No. 49: Abbott, Mrs. John Stevens Cabot, 1862 (Box 69, Folder 1497)
  - No. 50: Owen, Robert Dale, 1842 (Box 69, Folder 1498)
  - No. 51: Simcoe, Elizabeth Posthuma (Gwillim), 1840 (Box 69, Folder 1499)
  - No. 52: Haberman, Sophie, 1900, 1911 (Box 69, Folder 1500)
  - No. 53: Ludlow, John, 1834 (Box 69, Folder 1501)
  - No. 54: Dix, Dorothea Lynde, [1868?] (Box 69, Folder 1502)
  - No. 55: Hersilia (brig), 1820-1821 (Box 69, Folder 1503)
  - No. 56: Otis, Joseph, 1778 (Box 69, Folder 1504)
  - No. 57: Asakawa, Kan'Ichi
    See: Kan'Ichi Asakawa Papers, Ms. Gr. No. 40
  - No. 58: Huntington, Henry Strong ca., 1907-1914 (Box 69, Folder 1505)
  - No. 59: Jefferson, Mark Sylvester William, 1966 (Box 69, Folder 1506)
  - No. 60: Shephard, Charles Upham, 1830 (Box 69, Folder 1507)
  - No. 61: Buffinton, Captain John, 1795-1797, 1805, undated (Box 69, Folder 1508-1510)
  - No. 62: Newell, Samuel and Harriet, 1812 (Box 69, Folder 1511)
  - No. 63: Russell, Irwin, undated (Box 69, Folder 1512)
  - No. 64: Sumner, Joseph, 1803-1806 (Box 70, Folder 1513)
  - No. 65: Willey, Calvin
    See: Bristol Family Papers, Ms. Gr. No. 101
  - No. 66: Dwight, Theodore
    See: Dwight Family Papers, Ms. Gr. No. 187
  - No. 67: Potter, Nathaniel, 1842 (Box 70, Folder 1514)
  - No. 68: Cogswell, Joseph Green, 1823 (Box 70, Folder 1515)
  - No. 69: Willets, A. & S., firm, 1822 (Box 70, Folder 1516)
  - No. 70: Smith, Carl, 1969 (Box 70, Folder 1517)
  - No. 71: Daggett, David L., 1971, undated (Box 70, Folder 1518)
  - No. 72: Thompson, Aaron, 1777-1782 (Box 70, Folder 1519)
  - No. 73: Fowler, James, family, 1796-1899 (Box 70, Folder 1520)
  - No. 74: Binney, Horace, 1824-1828 (Box 70, Folder 1521)
  - No. 75: Woodruff, John Hermon, 1858-1875, undated (Box 71, Folder 1522-1525)
  - No. 76: Johnson, Claudia Alta (Taylor), 1968 (Box 71, Folder 1526)
  - No. 77: Washington, Bushrod, 1828 (Box 71, Folder 1527)
  - No. 78: Brown, John, 1851-1859 (Box 71, Folder 1528)
  - No. 79: Bryan, William Jennings, 1899-1921, undated (Box 71, Folder 1529)
  - No. 80: Larson, James Kenneth, 1950-1973 (Box 71, Folder 1530-1532)
  - No. 81: Kent, Roger
    See: Roger Kent Papers, Ms. Gr. No. 1401
  - No. 82: George, Jean, 1956 (Box 72, Folder 1533-1534)
  - No. 83: Bush, Prescott Sheldon, 1954 (Box 72, Folder 1535)
  - No. 84: Girard, Pierre Simon, 1830 (Box 72, Folder 1536)
  - No. 85: Hooper, Innis, 1772 (Box 72, Folder 1537)
  - No. 86: Quesada, Juan Nepomuceno de, Governor of Florida, 1794 (Box 72, Folder 1538)
  - No. 87: New Orleans: 3 citizens, Circa 1816 (Box 72, Folder 1539)
  - No. 88: Céspedes, Vicente Manuel de, Governor of Florida, 1787 (Box 72, Folder 1540)
  - No. 89: Flynn, P. W., 1832 (Box 72, Folder 1541)
  - No. 90: Parker, Isaac, 1798, [1817?] (Box 72, Folder 1542)
  - No. 91: O'Fallon, James, 1790-1791 (Box 72, Folder 1543)
  - No. 92: Gotear, Josiah, 1797-1801, undated (Box 72, Folder 1544)
  - No. 93: Golden, Cadwallader, 1761 (Box 72, Folder 1545)
  - No. 94: Davis, Jefferson, 1854 (Box 72, Folder 1546)
  - No. 95: Hitt [Plitt?], George, 1836 (Box 72, Folder 1547)
  - No. 96: Bates, Edward, 1861, 1864 (Box 72, Folder 1548)
  - No. 97: Gillespie, Joseph, 1874 (Box 72, Folder 1549)
  - No. 98: Lincoln, Robert Todd, 1924 (Box 72, Folder 1550)
  - No. 99: Nicolay, John George, 1898 (Box 72, Folder 1551)
  - No. 100: Shellabarger, Samuel, 1865 (Box 72, Folder 1552)
- Numerical, 101-200, Series XV
  - No. 101: Philbrick, C. H., 1864 (Box 73, Folder 1553)
  - No. 102: Volk, Leonard Wells, 1865 (Box 73, Folder 1554)
  - No. 103: Lefroy, John Henry, 1843-1844 (Box 73, Folder 1555)
    Existence and Location of Copies
    Journals of Sir John Lefroy are available on microfilm (1 reel, 35mm.) from Manuscripts and Archives, Yale University Library, at cost. Order no. HM42.
    Biographical / Historical
    John Henry Lefroy, soldier, scientist, and surveyor, was born in the village of Ashe, Hampshire, England on January 28, 1817. After attending private schools in Alton and Richmond he was entered as an officer-cadet in the Royal Military Academy at Woolwich in January of 1831. In December of 1834 he was gazetted second lieutenant in the Royal Artillery and in 1837 promoted to lieutenant and posted to Chatham.
    In the spring of 1839, acting on a proposal which had been made by Alexander Von Humboldt three years earlier, the British Government decided to establish a number of magnetic observatories throughout the British Empire. In conjunction with this, a number of specially selected officers were sent to Dublin to receive instructions in the use of scientific instruments under Professor Humphrey Lloyd of Trinity College. Among them was Lieutenant J. H. Lefroy.
    After several weeks of training in Dublin, he was sent to the island of St. Helena for further experience where he remained until July of 1842 when he was sent to take charge of the observatory which had been recently opened in Toronto, Canada West. In April of 1843, Lefroy, with a number of assistants and voyageurs, set out on a magnetic surveying expedition into the Northwest territories of Canada which lasted until November of 1844, and established, among other things, an approximate position of the magnetic North Pole.
    In 1853, Lefroy, by then a Captain, was recalled to England, where he continued his military duties and scientific interests. From 1871 to 1877 he served as Governor and Commander-in-Chief of the Bermudas; and from 1880 to 1882 as Governor of Tasmania. John Henry Lefroy died on April 11, 1890 in Cornwall, England. For additional information regarding Lefroy, see George F. G. Stanley, editor, John Henry Lefroy In Search of the Magnetic North - A Soldier-Surveyor's Letters from the North-West 1843-1844 (Toronto, 1955).
    The journals represent, as near as it is possible to tell, all of the manuscript volumes that Lefroy kept as a daily account of both his scientific readings and his personal observations while on the magnetic surveying expedition mentioned above. These volumes were believed to have been lost in 1846 (cf. Stanley, page i and the frontispiece to page 1) but in 1972 they were discovered in the Loomis-Wilder Famiily Papers (MS 496A) in the Yale University Library.
    Volume 1 ("Journal 1843") covers the period May 1 to September 23, 1843 and contains daily magnetic readings taken by Lefroy and members of the expedition. In addition, for each daily entry there are personal comments describing the weather, the geology, flora and fauna of the region, various events in the course of the expedition, and comments on Indian tribes encountered. Volume 2 ("Journal 1844") covering the period March 26 to November 18, 1844 is of a slightly different format, containing less and more informally recorded scientific information. There is, however, a consequently greater proportion of detailed personal observations which in this volume are interspersed with sketches made by Lefroy of various geologic phenomena, plants, tools, and Indians.
  - No. 104: Caroline Amelia Elizabeth, Queen of England, 1797-1821 (Box 74, Folder 1556-1558)
  - No. 105: Alden, Carroll Storrs, 1897-1933 (Box 75, Folder 1559-1561)
  - No. 106: Gage, Lot, 1835 (Box 75, Folder 1562)
  - No. 107: Schlösser, J., 1765 (Box 75, Folder 1563)
  - No. 108: Morris, Robert W., 1847 (Box 75, Folder 1564)
  - No. 109: Keep, Robert Porter, 1876 (Box 75, Folder 1565)
  - No. 110: MacArthur, Douglas, 1943-1945 (Box 75, Folder 1566)
  - No. 111: Yale, Calvin, 1801-1882 (Box 75, Folder 1567)
  - No. 112: Sumner, Charles, 1865, undated (Box 75, Folder 1568)
  - No. 113: Bancroft, George W., 1817-1818, 1838-1841, undated (Box 75, Folder 1569)
  - No. 114: Marshall, Henry Rutgers, 1894-1895 (Box 76, Folder 1570)
  - No. 115: Baldwin, George Rumford, 1846-1847 (Box 76, Folder 1571)
  - No. 116: Hall family, 1838-1854 (Box 76, Folder 1572)
  - No. 117: Prescott & Sherman, New Haven, 1797-1798 (Box 76, Folder 1573)
  - No. 118: Hail, William James, undated (Box 76, Folder 1574)
  - No. 119: Frank, Leslie, 1949 (Box 76, Folder 1575)
  - No. 120: Wade, Benjamin Franklin, 1838 (Box 76, Folder 1576)
  - No. 121: Hempstead, C[harles?] S., 1836 (Box 76, Folder 1577)
  - No. 122: Pickens, Francis Wilkinson, 1855 (Box 76, Folder 1578)
  - No. 123: Bailey, Theodorus, 1854-1857 (Box 76, Folder 1579)
  - No. 124: Voorhees, Ralph, 1829-1834 (Box 76, Folder 1580)
  - No. 125: Gould, Sarah C., 1824, 1828-1830 (Box 76, Folder 1581)
  - No, 126: Fulton, Robert, 1798 (Box 77, Folder 1582)
  - No. 127: Afro-American Studies Interviews
    - Bontemps, Arna, and Aaron Douglas, 1971 (Box 77, Folder 1583)
    - Boyd, Bob, 1972 (Box 77, Folder 1584)
    - Douglas, Aaron, 1972 (Box 77, Folder 1585)
    - Duncan, Danny, 1972 (Box 77, Folder 1586)
    - Irvin, Monte, 1972 (Box 77, Folder 1587)
    - Kennedy, Adrienne, 1972 (Box 77, Folder 1588)
    - Lovell, John, 1972 (Box 77, Folder 1589)
    - Robinson, Jackie, 1972 (Box 77, Folder 1590)
    - Sanders, Tom, 1972 (Box 77, Folder 1591)
    - Watkins, LeRoy, Sr., [1971-1972] (Box 77, Folder 1592)
    - Wesley, Richard, 1972 (Box 77, Folder 1593)
  - No. 128: Bunnell, Rufus William
    See: Bunnell Family Papers, Ms. Gr. No. 1149
  - No. 129: Silliman, Benjamin Douglas, 1852-1894 (Box 77, Folder 1594)
  - No. 130: Walker, Cam, 1965 (Box 77, Folder 1595)
  - No. 131: Creighton, James H., 1838, 1864 (Box 77, Folder 1596)
  - No. 132: Colquhoun, Patrick, 1791 (Box 77, Folder 1597)
  - No. 133: Laussat, Pierre Clément de, baron, 1803 (Box 77, Folder 1598)
  - No. 134: McGillavray, Alexander, 1789 (Box 77, Folder 1599)
  - No. 135: Buffalo, N.Y., 1819-1821 (Box 77, Folder 1600)
  - No. 136: Wood-worth, W. W., 1861 (Box 77, Folder 1601)
  - No. 137: Bishop, Abraham, 1804-1844 (Box 77, Folder 1602-1603)
  - No. 138: Maclay, Archibald, 1824 (Box 78, Folder 1604)
  - No. 139: Wallace, Henry Agard, 1945 (Box 78, Folder 1605)
  - No. 140: Beard, Augustus Field, 1859-1934, undated (Box 78, Folder 1606)
  - No. 141: Gould, Clarence Pembroke, undated (Box 78, Folder 1607-1609)
  - No. 142: Lambert, Asael Carlyle, [ca. 1969?] (Box 78, Folder 1610-1611)
  - No. 143: Stearns, George Luther, 1861-1864 (Box 79, Folder 1612)
  - No. 144: Turnbull, Thomas, 1787 (Box 79, Folder 1613)
  - No. 145: Kent, Lindley Coates, 1880 (Box 79, Folder 1614)
  - No. 146: Cadwalader, Thomas, 1810, 1814 (Box 79, Folder 1615)
  - No. 147: Izard, George, 1812 (Box 79, Folder 1616)
  - No. 148: Boyd, John Parker, 1815 (Box 79, Folder 1617)
  - No. 149: Debs, Eugene Victor, 1909-1926 (Box 79, Folder 1618)
  - No. 150: Maclure, William, 1834-1841, undated (Box 79, Folder 1619)
  - No. 151: Gillette, William
    See: James H. Penniman Papers, Ms. Gr. No. 9
  - No. 152: Fish, Nicholas, 1785-1786 (Box 79, Folder 1620)
  - No. 153: Wavell, Archibald Percival Wavell, 1st earl of, 1946-1948 (Box 79, Folder 1621)
  - No. 154: Lisca, Alessandro da, 1815 (Box 79, Folder 1622)
  - No. 155: Pierce, Elbridge Bancroft, Collection, 1793-1898, undated (Box 79, Folder 1623)
  - No. 156: Dixon, Alan C. Memorial Collection, 1718-1903 (Box 79, Folder 1624)
  - No. 157: Putnam, James Osborne, 1830-1897, undated (Box 79, Folder 1625)
  - No. 158: Page, J. Seaver, 1855, 1872-1915, undated (Box 79, Folder 1626)
  - No. 159: Bowler, Metcalf, 1776 (Box 79, Folder 1627)
  - No. 160: Saybrook, Conn. Second Society, 1793 (Box 79, Folder 1628)
  - No. 161: Phelps, William Lyon
    See: William Lyon Phelps Papers, Ms. Gr. No. 578
  - No. 162: Woodbridge, Conn. First Church, 1738-1939 (Box 80, Folder 1629-1630)
  - No. 163: Grote, Harriet, 1836 (Box 80, Folder 1631)
  - No. 164: Henry, Patrick, and George Rogers Clark, 1974 (Box 80, Folder 1632)
  - No. 165: Bumstead, Henry Andrews, 1918, 1920 (Box 80, Folder 1633)
  - No. 166: Trotskii, Lev, 1936-1938 (Box 81, Folder 1634)
  - No. 167: Fenner, Martha, Circa 1812 (Box 81, Folder 1635)
  - No. 168: Wandycz, Damian S., 1952 (Box 81, Folder 1636)
  - No. 169: Bartlett, Josiah and Mary, 1775-1778 (Box 81, Folder 1637)
  - No. 170: Heintz, Stephen Brodhead, 1974 (Box 81, Folder 1638)
  - No. 171: Nehru, Jawaharlal, 1963 (Box 81, Folder 1639)
  - No. 172: Coombs, Philip Hall, 1951-1952 (Box 81, Folder 1640-1641)
  - No. 172: Coombs, Philip Hall, 1952-1960 (Box 82, Folder 1642-1645)
  - No. 173: Frazer, Persifor, 1776-1778, 1840 (Box 82, Folder 1646)
  - No. 174: Dooly, John, 1779 (Box 82, Folder 1647)
  - No. 175: Gilpin, Thomas, 1777-1778 (Box 82, Folder 1648)
  - No. 176: U.S. Army. Continental Army, undated (Box 82, Folder 1649)